hello and welcome to the second tutorial
on how to program in g-script 2.
in the last tutorial i showed you how to
download the files
remote control and level editor that'll
help you with gscript 2.
in this tutorial i'm going to show you
how to use them or at least upload a
level
and a bit in rc first let's open the
level editor
and let's create a new level it's new 9
i guess
and let's add an npc into it there
let's put it anywhere and open the
script
this script is in juice script one if we
pressed run
it would work if we made this g script
two
and press play or run it would not work
because level editor does not work
with gscript 2. however
g-script 1 is 95 backwards compatible
online
so if this this would actually work
online it just wouldn't be very flexible
it's just not as good as if we uploaded
a g script 2
script so anyway let's just save this
instead of changing it to script 2
and save it into our little tutorials
folder
save next let's lower this
and bring out rc
click this button here this shows all
the files and folders
on your server like images and levels
if you own a server you'll usually have
the rights for these things unless your
ip
changes or maybe you take them off
yourself for whatever reason
if you're working on someone else's
server they'll have to give you the
rights to these folders
anyway to upload a file we click
right click and press upload file or do
it the easy way
we can go find our folder that contains
the level here and just
drag it in just drag it in
it'll create a new level after name of
what file you uploaded
or if we uploaded a pre-existing one
it'll just update the
level next we want to warp the level
new 9 and w
and you can see our little npc here
he doesn't do much but we haven't really
programmed to do anything
now on room control i'm going to explain
at least a few of the buttons and save
others for the next tutorial this one
here
at the top left corner lets you change
all
lets you pretty much configure all the
players on your server
like this is me i can change my rights i
can change my attributes i can change
folders i can access i can ban myself
which i'm not going to do
i can reset myself i can disconnect
myself
you get it this one at the
top right corner but not at the very top
right corner
is the flags button this one is needed
for g-script 2
because it lets you it's like data on
the server
so if we had it actually i'll get into
it later but just know this is pretty
useful g-script too
these three buttons here this one this
one
and this one are the scripts that are on
the server
we'll get into them and what they do
later but anyway this concludes
our second tutorial on how to program a
g-script ii
i hope you you at least have an idea of
how to upload files
and at least a fan idea of what g
of what rc does so bye